In this video, we're gonna to work through a couple of SLR parsing examples. So let's
在这段视频中，我们将演练几个单反解析示例。所以让我们
do a very simple example. Let's consider the grammar. S goes to SA, or S goes to B.
做一个非常简单的例子。让我们来考虑一下语法。S归SA，或S归B。
And what does this grammar do? It produces strings of A's followed by a B. So any
那么这个语法是做什么的呢？它会产生A后跟B的字符串。所以任何
number of A's followed by a single B.  And notice that the grammar is left recursive,
A的数量后面跟着一个B，注意语法是左递归的，
and recall that that's not a problem for a bottom up parser. Slr parsers, LR parsers,
回想一下，这对于自下而上的解析器来说不是问题。SLR解析器、LR解析器
are perfectly happy with left recursive grammars. So let's begin by working out
对左递归语法非常满意。所以让我们从健身开始
what the automaton for this, grammar should be, what the parsing automaton
它的自动机是什么，语法应该是什么，解析自动机是什么
should be. And recall that the first step is to add a new production to the grammar.
应该是的。回想一下，第一步是将新的结果添加到语法中。
We have to add a new start symbol. That all it does, it has one production that
我们必须添加一个新的开始符号。它所做的一切，它只有一部作品
goes to the old start symbol. And that's, again, just for technical reasons. Now,
转到旧的开始符号。再说一次，这只是出于技术原因。现在,
the start symbol, or sorry, the start state of the NFA of the parsing automaton
开始符号，或对不起，解析自动机的NFA的开始状态
is this item. S prime, our new start symbol, goes to dot S, our old start
就是这件东西。S质数，我们的新开始符号，去到点S，我们的旧起点
symbol. And rather than build the NFA, and then do the subset of states construction.
符号。而不是构建NFA，然后进行状态子集构建。
Let's just go ahead and work out what items must be in the first state of the
让我们继续并计算出哪些项必须处于
DFA. So remember that all the epsilon moves in the, in the DF-, in the NFA, are
DFA。所以请记住，在DF-中，在NFA中，所有的epsilon移动都是
due to moves that happen because we don't see a non terminal on the stack. But
因为我们在堆栈上看不到非终端，所以发生了移动。但
instead see something derived from that non terminal. So if we have a dot, Right
相反，可以看到从非终端派生内容。所以如果我们有一个圆点，对吗？
next to a non terminal. That means that there's an epsilon move in the NFA to all
紧挨着一个非终点站。这意味着在NFA中有一个ε移动到所有人
the items that have, for all the productions, all the, all the first items,
对于所有的作品，所有的，所有的第一个项目，
for the productions of that non terminal. What do I mean by that? I mean that this
为那个非终结者的作品。我这么说是什么意思？我是说这个
state, I mean epsilon production to S goes to dot SA. So this is the first item in
国家，我的意思是ε生产到S到点SA。所以这是第一件物品
recognizing, this production. So the dots all the way at the left, And there would
认识到，这部作品。所以所有的点都在左边，那里会
also be an item for the other production for S, S goes to dot B. Alright, so that's
也是S的另一部作品的项目，S去了点B。好的，那就是
the epsilon closure in the NFA of this start item. So this'll be the first state.
此开始项的NFA中的epsilon闭合。所以这将是第一个州。
These three things, these three items would be the first state of the DFA. And
这三件事，这三件事就是DFA的第一个状态。和
now we have to consider what would happen on each of the possible transitions for
现在，我们必须考虑在每个可能的转换上会发生什么
each of the symbols that we might see on the stack. So let's think about what
我们可能在堆栈上看到的每一个符号。所以让我们想一想
happens if we see a B. So if we see a B on the stack, then the only item that's going
如果我们看到一个B就会发生。所以如果我们在堆栈上看到一个B，那么唯一要处理的项目
to be in that state is S goes to B dot okay? So it'll be fine to see a B and this
处于那种状态就是S去B点，好吗？所以看一个B和这个会很好的
would be the only item that was valid for the stack contents. Now another
将是堆栈内容唯一有效的项。现在又来了一个
possibility is that we'll see an S. So, if we see an S on the stack, what will
有可能我们会看到一个S。那么，如果我们在堆栈上看到一个S，那会是什么呢？
happen? Well, we're going to go to a state that has two items. S prime goes to S dot,
发生了什么？好，我们要去一个有两个项目的州。S的质数是S点，
so that we've seen S on the stack, and we're ready to reduce by, by this
所以我们已经在堆栈上看到了S，我们已经准备好通过这个来减少
production, possibly. And also, S goes to S. A. And now, Clearly in this state let's
可能是制作。还有，S去了S.A.，现在，很明显，在这个状态下，让我们
talk about his state down here. There are no more transitions possible. In all there
在这里谈论他的状态。不可能有更多的过渡。总而言之，在那里
is only one item in the state dots all the way at the right hand side, so that state
状态中只有一项一直点在右手边，所以状态
is completely done. In this state the one over here on the right side. While one of
已经完全完成了。在这个州，右边的那个。而其中一个
these items is complete, the dot's all the way at the right. But the other item still
这些都是完整的，圆点一直在右边。但是另一件物品仍然
has an A, so there could be one more transition out of this state. To the item,
有一个A，所以这个状态可能还会有一个转变。到物品上，
S goes to SA dot, Alright? And now if we look at this, we see that for the most
S去SA点，好吗？现在如果我们看这个，我们看到的最多的是
part these states are in pretty good shape. So these two states this one down
部分这些州的状况相当不错。所以这两个状态这一个向下
here and this one over here, they only have a single item, and so there's no
这里和那里，他们只有一件物品，所以没有
possibility of a shift reduce conflict in those states. There's only one item,
转变的可能性减少了这些州的冲突。只有一件东西，
there's only one thing to do. The only possibility here in both of these states
只有一件事可以做。在这两个州唯一的可能性是
is to reduce. This state, the initial start state, has no reduce moves. So it's
就是减少。此状态(初始启动状态)没有Reduce移动。所以这就是
only shift moves here, so there can't be a shift reduce conflict, because there are
只有移位才能在这里移动，所以不可能有移位减少冲突，因为
no reduce items, No possible reduce actions. And there is to reduce, reduce
没有减少项目，没有可能的减少操作。还有就是减少，减少
conflicts for the same reason. The only state of interest really for the point of
出于同样的原因发生冲突。唯一令人感兴趣的状态就是
view for what who the grammar is SLR1 is this middle state. And here we can either
语法是什么的视图SLR1就是这个中间状态。在这里我们可以
reduce by s prime goes to s dot, or we could shift and A onto the stack. And the
减去s素数就是s点，或者我们可以把A移位到堆栈上。以及
question is, what is in the follow of S prime? So what can follow S prime in the
问题是，紧跟在S素数后面的是什么？那么在S素数之后可以有什么呢？
grammar? And if we look back up at our grammar, we'll see that nothing can follow
语法？如果我们回顾一下我们的语法，我们会发现没有什么是可以遵循的
S prime. S prime is the start symbol, and so, in fact, the only thing in the follow
这是质数。的素数是开始符号，所以，实际上，后面唯一的
of S prime is the, And to the input. And so what that tells us is that we'll reduce
是S素数的，和是输入。所以这告诉我们，我们将减少
by s prime, goes to s, if, if we're out of input. And otherwise if there is an A on
除以s素数，如果输入不足，则转到s。否则，如果上面有A
the stack, sorry, if there's an a in the input, then we'll shift it onto the stack.
堆栈，对不起，如果输入中有a，那么我们会把它移到堆栈上。
And so this grammar is, SLR1. There are no shift reduce, or reduce, reduce conflicts
所以这个语法是，SLR1。不存在移位减少，或减少，减少冲突
implied by this parsing automaton. Let's do another example, slightly more complex.
这个解析自动机所暗示的。让我们再举一个例子，稍微复杂一点。
In fact, let's just extend the previous grammar. We'll have a, a production. S
实际上，让我们只扩展前面的语法。我们会有一部，一部作品。%s
goes to SAS, okay? So now we have the non terminal twice with an A in between, Or S
去特种部队，好吗？所以现在我们有两次非终结符，中间有一个A，或者S
can go to B, just like before. And now let's work out the parsing automaton for
可以去B，就像以前一样。现在让我们计算出以下内容的解析自动机
this grammar. And, once again, We'll need to add a dummy start symbol To the grammar
这个语法。再一次，我们需要在语法中添加一个虚拟开始符号
And it will go. It's only production will be to, generate the old start symbol. And
它会消失的。它唯一的制作将是，生成旧的开始符号。和
now let's begin working out what's in the, parsing automaton, for this particular
现在，让我们开始计算解析自动机中的内容，针对这个特定的
grammar. And, and just like before, we're not going to go through the effort of
语法。而且，就像以前一样，我们不会像以前那样
constructing, the NFA. That would be a systematic way to do it. One way to it is,
建设，NFA。这将是一种系统的方式来做这件事。一种方法是，
is the way we sketched. Was just to construct the NFA first, and then do the
是我们素描的方式。就是先建造NFA，然后再做
subset of states construction. But, this grammar is small enough. And simple enough
状态子集构造。但是，这个语法已经足够小了。而且足够简单
that we can work out directly what is in, what are in the states, what items are in
我们可以直接计算出什么在里面，什么在美国，什么东西在里面
the states of DFA. So just like before because the dart here is immediately next
DFA的状态。所以就像以前一样，因为这里的省道就是下一个
to the S, we know that we can without consuming any input at all make an epsilon
对于S，我们知道我们可以在不消耗任何输入的情况下制作ε
transition in the interface to the items that start the productions for S. So these
在界面中转换到开始S的生产的项目。所以这些
will be in the, also in the DFA state. And that's it. We can't add any other,
将处于，也处于DFA状态。就这样了。我们不能再加其他的了，
productions here. So S is the only non terminal. And we've added all the, first
在这里制作。所以S是唯一的非终结点。我们已经添加了所有的，首先
items, initial items for S. And so that is the complete state. Okay? So just like
项目，S的初始项目，这就是完整状态。好吧?所以就像
before, one possibility is that we'll see a B on the stack. And so that would give
在此之前，一种可能性是我们会在堆栈上看到B。所以这会给你带来
us the item S goes to B dot. And that's the only item valid for that state.
我们把物品S送到B点。这是该州唯一有效的项目。
Another possibility is that we'll see an S on the stack. Okay? In which case, we'll
另一种可能性是，我们将在堆栈上看到S。好吧?那样的话，我们就
make a transition to the state, S prime goes to S dot. And S goes to S dot AS,
转换到状态，S‘转到S点。S转到S点，
alright? So we saw that same state before, in the, in the other automaton. Now we
好吗？所以我们之前在，在另一个自动机中看到了同样的状态。现在我们
could also see an A. Now what state would that take us to? And this is going to be a
也可以看到一个A。现在，这会把我们带到什么州呢？这将是一个
little different. In this state, we could have the item, or will have the item, SA
有点不同。在此状态下，我们可以拥有项目，也可以拥有项目SA
dot S, and I notice that the dot is right next to S, so instead of seeing an S on
点S，我注意到点就在S旁边，所以不是看到S
the set, we could also see something derived from S in the next position on
集合，我们还可以看到从S派生的东西在下一个位置上
this stack. And so we have to throw in all the productions for S. There's only two of
这一堆。所以我们必须把S的所有作品都放进去，只有两部
them. But that means we could have the item S goes to dot SAS, and S goes to dot
他们。但这意味着我们可以让项目S转到点SAS，S转到点
P. Alright, and then out of this state, now there are a couple of different
好的，然后离开这个州，现在有几个不同的
possible transitions, we could see an S or we could see a B. Well, if we see a B,
可能的转变，我们可以看到S，也可以看到B。如果我们看到B，
then we wind up in this state over here. And if we see an S, Well, what's going to
然后我们就到了这里的这个州。如果我们看到一个S，那么，
happen? If we see an S, then we'll wind up in another new state. Where we have, S
发生了什么？如果我们看到S，那么我们将进入另一个新的州。在我们有的地方，S
goes to SAS dot. We've seen the complete right hand side of that production. Or S
转到SAS点。我们已经看到了那部作品的完整右手边。或S
goes to SA.S. Actually, that dot's in the wrong place, so let's erase that, and
去了SA.S。实际上，那个点放错了位置，所以我们把它擦掉，然后
let's put it in the right place. It's right here. Before the A, not after the A.
让我们把它放在正确的位置。就在这里。在A之前，不是在A之后。
Alright and now we have to think about what happens in this state. So in this
好的，现在我们必须考虑在这个状态下会发生什么。所以在这件事上
state the only possible input is an A and if it isn't A, what's we going to have,
唯一可能的输入是A，如果不是A，我们会得到什么，
we're going to have S goes to SA.S and then we're gonna have to add the initial
我们将S转换为Sa，然后我们必须添加首字母
productions for S again. And so that would just take us back to this state and like
再次为S制作。所以这会把我们带回这个状态，就像
other transition labels too we go to this state on an S and we come back to that
其他过渡标签也是如此，我们在S上转到这个状态，然后回到那个状态
state, the bottom state here for the top state on an A. And I think if we hadn't
州，这是A的最高州的最低州，我认为如果我们没有
made any mistakes that, that is the complete transition system and all the
犯了任何错误，那就是完整的过渡系统和所有
states for this DFA. Now the question is, is this , is this parsing automaton is it,
此DFA的国家/地区。现在的问题是，这是不是，这个解析自动机是不是，
this is, is this the parsing automaton of a, a solar one grammar. And in order to
这是，这是一个一个，一个太阳音文法的句法自动机。并且为了
answer that question we have to look for possible reduce, reduce, and shift reduce
回答这个问题，我们必须寻找可能的Reduce、Reduce和Shift Reduce
conflict. Well a quick scan of all the states here will show you or convince you
冲突。嗯，快速浏览一下这里的所有州，就会向你展示或说服你
that there are not. Any states, where there are two possible reduce-moves. So
那就是没有。任何州，其中有两个可能的缩减移动。所以
there can't be any reduce reuse conflicts in this, in this automaton. We can ignore
在这个自动机中，不可能有任何减少重用的冲突。我们可以忽略
states that only have a single item or states that have no possible reduce-moves
只有一个项目的状态或没有可能减少移动的状态
at all. Because, those are states in which there cannot be a shift-reduce conflict
完全没有。因为，在这些状态下，不可能存在转移-减少冲突
and that means we can ignore these two states. The two states over here at the
这意味着我们可以忽略这两种状态。在这里的两个州
extreme left. So now we're left with these three states to think about. Alright, so
最左边。所以现在我们只剩下这三个州要考虑了。好的，那么
we look at this state last time. As before, the follow of S prime Is just
上一次我们看到了这种状态。和以前一样，S素数的后面只是
equal to the dollar sign. And so there's no shift reduce conflict in this state
等于美元符号。所以在这个州没有转移减少冲突
Because on, on input A we can only shift. We can't reduce by S prime goes to S. All
因为在输入A上，我们只能移位。我们不能减去S，素数都是S
right, and now we're down looking at these two states. And let's just consider this
好的，现在我们向下看这两个州。让我们考虑一下这一点
bottom state first. Alright, so what does this state say to do? Well, this state
最低态优先。好的，那么这个州说该怎么做？那么这个州呢，
says, that well first of all, observe. That, the only transitions out of this
说，那好，首先，观察一下。那就是，唯一走出这一步的过渡
state are on B and S and there are no reduced moves in this state at all, so
状态在B和S上，并且在此状态下根本没有减少的移动，因此
there's no possibility of a shift reduce conflict in this state either. That leaves
在这个州，减少冲突也是不可能的。那就剩下
us with just this state to think about. Now this state does have a reduced move,
我们只需要考虑这个州。现在这个州的动作确实减少了，
the first item here is a, is a reduction, and that says that we should reduce by S
这里的第一项是a，是减去，也就是说我们应该减去S
goes to S A S if whatever comes next is in the follow of S, so we're gonna need to
如果接下来的任何事情都在S之后，那么我们就需要去S-S，所以我们需要
know what's in the follow of S. Well from S prime goes to S, we know that anything
知道S后面的是什么，从S到S，我们知道
that's in the follow of S prime is in the follow of S. So clearly dollar is in the
这是在S质数之后，S是在S之后，所以很明显美元在
follow of S. And then from this part of the grammar here, we can see that A is in
跟在S后面，然后从语法的这一部分我们可以看出A在
the follow of S. And then from this occurrence here of S, we know that since
跟在S后面，然后从这里发生的S，我们知道因为
it occurs at the, the far right side of the production, that an ything in the
它发生在制作的最右边，那就是
follow of the right hand side, the left hand side non terminal, is also gonna be
紧随右手边，左手边非终点站，也将是
in follow of S. Well, in this case they're the same. It just says that the follow of
在S后面，在这种情况下，它们是一样的。它只是说下面的
S is a subset of the follow of S which is trivially always true, and so it doesn't
S是S的Follow的子集，S的Follow几乎总是正确的，所以它不是
add anything new. And so we wind up with just the follow of S being just two
添加任何新内容。所以我们最后得到的结果是S的后面只有两个
things, dollar sign and A. But that poses a problem, because this says that if we
美元符号和A，但这带来了一个问题，因为这说的是，如果我们
see an A in the input we should reduce. And this move here says that if we see an
在我们应该减少的输入中看到一个A。这一举动表明，如果我们看到一个
A in the input, we should shift. And so, this state does have a shift-reduce
A在输入时，我们应该换挡。因此，这种状态确实有一个移位-减去(Shift-Reduce)
conflict. Alright, and so this grammar is not SLR what.
冲突。好的，所以这个语法不是SLR什么。